

## Mustafa Kamal B. Yaakub

**Expertise: Engineering Project Management** 

Sector/Industry: Manufacturing-Automotive

### PERSONAL PARTICULARS

Full Name : Mustafa Kamal B. Yaakub

IC Number : 760922-08-5787

Gender : Male

Age: 37 years old

Date of Birth: 22<sup>nd</sup> September 1976
Place of Birth: Bota Kanan, Perak

Nationality : Malaysian
Status : Married
Race : Malay
Health : Excellent

Height / Weight : 165cm / 75 kg Current Address : No 24 Jalan 4C.

> Taman Jati, 4800 Rawang,

Selangor Darul Ehsan.

Telephone Number : 012-371-8290

E-Mail : dinadany0405@gmaill.com

### **SUMMARY**

Well experienced in setup new heavy and high-tech machinery, conducted retrofit of CNC machine and refurbishment of ageing press machine (up to 1500T). Successfully experienced in manage a team for major installation of new tandem robot system integrated with old stamping press line from feasibility study, technical evaluation until trial and commissioning stage. Various experienced in project engineering management with local vendor and foreign companies (e.g. ABB Korea & Sweden, Komatsu Japan, Hitachi Japan, Lien Cheh Machinery- Taiwan and etc.) Participate in collaboration activity with local universities as internship co-supervisor, conducted short seminars, industrial advisor for Engineering faculty and Robot donation to 3 universities. Well experienced working with Japanese expatriate in various machine

installations and improvement especially with Daihatsu Motor Japan counterpart.

## **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

### Jan 2008~2010:

## International Islamic University Malaysia.

Achievement: Master of Science in Manufacturing Engineering.

Result CGPA: 3.33

Project Paper: Dust Prevention System for Stamping Press Shop.

### April 1996~1999:

## Ibaraki National College of Technology, Japan.

Achievement: Associate Degree in Electronics & Control Engineering.

## April 1994~1996:

## Universiti Teknologi Malaysia

Preparatory Center for Technical Studies to Japan Program.

Achievement: 1) Program Certificate

2) Full Attendance Award

3) Japanese Language Proficiency Level 3

#### January 1989~1993:

## Sekolah Sains Raja Tun Azlan Shah, Taiping Perak.

SPM: Grade 1

#### LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Language	Spoken	Written
Bahasa Malaysia	10	10
English	8	8
Japanese	8	8

## **WORKING EXPERIENCES**

### August 2003~Current

## Perodua Manufacturing Sdn Bhd

Job Function: Assistant Manager, Facilities Engineering Section, Project Team Department - (Press Engineering).

Major Responsibility:

- 1. Lead a team for factory plant improvement and upgrading activities in Stamping Press Shop, Perodua.
- 2. Lead a team and responsible in engineering design, cost evaluation,

specification discussion with vendors, installation and commissioning work for every new plant improvement project in Stamping Press Shop.

- 3. Planning for staff's Human Development System and continuous learning and improvement.
- Responsible in forecasting production capacity and do countermeasure to solve insufficient production loading problem.
- 5. Giving technical advice and consulting to local vendors for production and capacity improvement.
- 7. Collaborate with technical partner from various parties such as Daihatsu Japan, machine maker Hitachi Fukui, Komatsu Japan, ABB Korea, ABB Sweden and etc for plant improvement activities which require details feasibility study and technical discussion.
- 8. Planning and execute Preventive Maintenance activities of ageing equipment which include overall machine inspection by machine maker, budget proposal for management approval, manpower arrangement and co-ordination between local and foreign expertise during parts replacement.
- 9. Main coordinator for developing new spare part control system which related to important machinery in whole factory. Responsible for monitoring the ongoing system mechanism is running smoothly by the end user i.e. Facility Maintenance Department.

#### Dec 2001~July 2003

Ultimate Technologies Asia (M) Sdn Bhd.
Ultimate Technologies Inc (Japan) Co. Ltd
(1 Year stationed at Nagano, Japan)

Job Function: PCB Design Engineer

1. Involve in circuit and PCB circuit board design for SONY and TOSHIBA Japan products such as Digital TV, Digital Camera, Card Reader, Modem and Tuner. Used design software from ZUKEN, Mentor Graphics and Valor.

### March 1999~Nov 2001

## Sharp Electronics Malaysia Sdn Bhd

Job Function: Asst. Engineer

1. Involve in circuit design and new model development for Video and TV products for SHARP products.

### INVOLVED as PROJECT LEADER in PERODUA

## Project Name: Double Blank Detection System

- Purpose: To eliminate problem due to double material stamping issue that occur at draw process (stamping). Collaborate with Daihatsu Japan to conduct in-house improvement activity with installation of LK series laser type sensor and modification at PLC at press machine.
- Contractor/Supplier: DAB(Malaysia), Keyence (Malaysia & Japan),
- Achievement: No major breakdown after installation.
- Project Name: Installation of new Robot System at Press Line 1B
- Purpose: Refurbishment of new Robot system at Press Line 1B by changing 6 units of ageing SK120robots with new ABB handling robots and refurbish robot and press machine communication system by upgrade to CC-Link system.
- Contractor/Supplier: ABB Malaysia & ABB Korea.
- Achievement: Production efficiency at Press Line 1B increases ~ 20%.

### Project Name: Blanking Scrap Recycling Activities

- Purpose: Cost reduction activity by recycling blank scrap from Panel Side Outer body panel for the use of other metal stamping parts.
- Achievement: Reduce cost car/unit by eliminating raw material cost.

## <u>Project Name: Forkless System for Stamping Press shop</u>

- Purpose: Implement new delivery/supply system for stamping parts with new concept of pallet design, storage layout, FIFO system and capacity study.
- Achievement: Reduce usage of forklifts, increase quality with dust quantity reduction from forklifts.

## Project Name: Dust Prevention System at Stamping Press shop

- Purpose: To reduce quality defect and production downtime due to bump and dent problems cause by contamination dust from outside and inside stamping press shop. Implemented activities were installation of dust partition, water mist fogger, Pull & Push system, water curtain and etc at stamping press area.
- Achievement: Quality defect and downtime reduced more than 30%.

### <u>Project Name: New Tooling System for Robot Fingers at Press Line 1B</u>

• Purpose: GSPH upgrading and improvement at Press Line 1B by

- eliminate breakdown and line stoppage due Robot miss loading and vacuum error. New robot tooling from ABB Sweden already installed with more flexible, cheap and full proof design.
- Contractors/Supplier: DAB Technology Sdn Bhd & ABB Sweden.
- Achievement: Production efficiency at Press Line 1B increases ~ 10%.

## Project Name: Installation of new Robot System at Press Line 2A

- Purpose: GSPH upgrading and improvement Press Line 2A by changing 2 units of unloader and loader robot with new ABB handling robots and refurbish robot and press machine communication system by upgrade to CC-Link system.
- Contractor/Supplier: ABB Malaysia & ABB Korea.
- Achievement: Production efficiency increases ~ 20%.

# <u>Project Name: Installation of new magnet floater at DF System Press Line</u> 1B

- Purpose: Eliminate double blank problems at DF Robot and Crane Saver at Press Line 1B by introduce new concept of magnet floater to separate material sheet from stick together and maintaining fanning angles for DB sensor functioning.
- Contractor/Supplier: Priority Engineering Services (Australia) Co. Ltd
- Achievement: Reduced downtime for double blank problems at 91%; Best Project Award In PE Department For Quality Campaign

### Project Name: Coil Storage Warehouse for Perodua.

- Purpose: Set up new warehouse and system for internal metal coils storage in Perodua. Being involved in capacity study, layout design and installation of 25 tonne overhead crane and others equipments.
- Consultant: Mitsui Japan.
- Achievement: Huge saving in operation and material cost.

## Others: Higher Institution (Local universities) Collaboration

- 1. Supervisor for internship students from IIUM, UTP, UNITEN, UNIKL-MSI, UMP, UTM, Polytechnic KPTM & University of Melbourne.
- 2. Conducted 2 short seminars at Unikl-IPROM for title "Cost Reduction in Automotive" and "Kaizen Continuous Improvement".
- 3. Main coordinator for Yaskawa-SK120 Robot Donation Activity to IIUM, UKM and UPM.
- 4. Industrial advisor for "Fakulti Kejuruteraan Elektrikal dan Elektronik Universiti Putra Malaysia".